Sidimar Gobbo

+55 19 99604-1615

in linkedin.com/in/sidimar

https://www.behance.net/sidimar

Summary

A user experience designer with more than 10 years of experience.

My main activities are understood what the users need and then advocate for them through user interview, lo-fi hi-fi design, usability test.

I have both Italian and Brazilian citizenship

Experience



UX Designer

May 2017 - Jan 2019

1 year 9 months

Thomson Reuters

- Organize and lead UX discovery workshops, persona building, journey mapping, and design exercises for key business segments within Thomson Reuters to identify enterprise solution opportunities.
- Conduct stakeholder interviews, 1-on-1's, and group interviews to assess and develop solutions for emerging content management products at Thomson Reuters Tax & Accounting.
- Run user interviews, identify key requirements, and storymap business-enhancing workflows.
- Develop user-research plans, and rapidly build test-ready product prototypes.
- Translate emerging business goals into actionable UX deliverables for leadership teams.
- Acting as product owner: scope and define user requirements, prioritize iteration stories, keep track of quarterly backlog health, run grooming sessions for emerging features.
- Work closely with UX and front-end teams to maintain brand-standard UI components.



UX / UI Designer

Jul 2013 - Mar 2017

The Examcraft Group

3 years 9 months

I've in Senior User Experience position for a school management software:

- Transform what the final users need in concept and visual design.
- Design thinking to understand better what the user really needs
- Prototype and test to validate the ideas and concepts before a high visual concept.
- Designed UX for a school management platform for student, teachers, parents, school staff using design thinking and prototype.
- Designed UX for the admin tool to manage users, groups, homework, school notice, etc.
- Developed to be a responsive platform and cross-browser.
- Developed for tablets and phone.
- Worked closely with users to inform and educate about UX best practices.
- Redesigned and applied a modern concept to old products.

http://www.typ.ie



Web Designer / UI Design

Jan 2010 - Apr 2013

Working on Drupal applications as a support team for websites to Johnson and Johnson, consumer products USA and Canada:

- Assessment, understanding, and resolution of issues opened by stakeholders and/or QA team.
- Solve issues with HTML, CSS, and Jquery inside Drupal.
- Leading a development team with 10 people inside support team.

Working on Drupal application development team for Centrum website to Pfizer, USA:

• Front-end developer, taking mockups in PSD and transforming in HTML, CSS inside Drupal.

Working on Microsoft Share Point application development team for Johnson and Johnson, USA IT team:

- Designed blog CEO Johnson and Johnson.
- Developed HTML, CSS to be responsive platform and cross-browser.
- Developed UX for tablets and phone.
- · Designed wireframes using Balsamiq.



Web Designer / UI Designer

Webcompany Agência Digital

Dec 2007 - Jan 2010

2 years 2 months

As a hybrid a designer, I worked on a variety of web projects for local and national clients like 3M. Interpreting designed layouts, creating original concepts, production, and webmaster tasks were all my responsibility.

Worked close with users to validated briefings and concepts for website, web commerce, huge campaigns, and quick campaigns.

Designed wireframes, mockups and final conceptions, validating the ideas with clients and team to generate more value and understanding for the whole project.

Education



Pontifícia Universidade Católica de São Paulo

2017 - 2017

UX DIGITAL: EXPERIÊNCIA DO USUÁRIO EM PLATAFORMAS DIGITAIS, UX Design, UX DIGITAL: EXPERIÊNCIA DO USUÁRIO EM PLATAFORMAS DIGITAIS

O curso Experiência do Usuário em Plataformas Digitais tem como objetivo preparar os participantes no conhecimento e aplicação de processos e métodos de concepção de produtos e serviços digitais que proporcionem uma experiência adequada aos seus usuários. Por meio de conceitos e ferramentas para exploração do projeto, elaboração de hipóteses, pesquisas com usuários, prototipação, testes e mensurações, o curso explora todo processo de elaboração de um projeto digital.

Aspectos como usabilidade, arquitetura de informação, design de interação, acessibilidade, fatores humanos, estratégia de conteúdo, pesquisas com usuários, serão tópicos abordados durante o curso para aprofundar o conhecimento sobre a área. Design para plataformas móveis, IoT e interfaces inovadoras também serão abordadas. O curso também irá abordar a prática do UX design junto aos métodos de desenvolvimento ágil e como atuar para ampliar a prática do design centrado no usuário dentro das empresas.



Universidade Paulista

2007 - 2009

Bachelor's Degree, Web Page, Digital/Multimedia and Information Resources Design

Activities and Societies: Comunicação Digital 2009



Universidade São Judas Tadeu

2005 - 2006

Associate's Degree, Advertising and Marketing, Social Comunication



English Language Academy (ELA)

English Language and Literature, General, Upper Intermediate A full intensive english course.

Skills



Design Thinking • User Interface Design • Paper Prototyping • HTML • CSS

Certifications

Design Kit: Prototyping • NovoEd 205876ae5d57f7 • Jul 2016 - Aug 2016 Design Kit: Prototyping • NovoEd 205876ae5d57f7 • Jul 2016 - Present

DESIGN KIT: THE COURSE FOR HUMAN-CENTERED DESIGN • NovoEd

Jan 2018 - Mar 2018